http://www.lucasfonts.com/privacy

Privacy policy
LucasFonts is firmly committed to our visitors’ privacy. LucasFonts undertakes to collect your data only when necessary to render you the services you require by means that are fair, legal and transparent.
Legal statement
The LucasFonts privacy policy statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination policy for the websites www.lucasfonts.com and www.fontfabrik.com (jointly referred to hereafter as: the LucasFonts website, or the/this website).
By visiting or using this website or receiving services, you agree to the terms of the then-current LucasFonts online privacy policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site or services.
LucasFonts reserves the right to change the online privacy policy at its sole discretion. Your continued use of our site following the posting of changes to these terms means that you accept these changes.
Hosting and access logging
The LucasFonts website is hosted on a web server provided by Amazon Web Services (AWS). The server is located in Frankfurt/Main, Germany.
Every visit of the LucasFonts website generates an entry in the access log on the web server. This log file contains the following information:
the IP address from which you issued the request
the date and time
the URL you requested
the URL of any page that referred you to the page
the type of browser and operating system you are using
and whether your request was successful.
Your IP adress will be anonymized, so that your visit of the LucasFonts website can not be assigned to a specific person. These log files are deleted by us from time to time.
AWS is a subsidiary of Amazon.com, Inc. or one of its affiliates. Please refer to Amazon’s privacy information: aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq.
Use of cookies
In order for the navigation of this website and its shopping system to work for you, information commonly known as ‘cookies’ get placed on your computer. A cookie is a piece of information that is placed on your computer by a web server and can only be read by the server that gave it to you. It functions as your identification card, helping to correlate your passwords, purchases, and preferences to your personal browser. It cannot be executed as code or deliver viruses.
If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may disable the cookie function in your browser. In this case, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the LucasFonts website.
LucasFonts will never use cookies to retrieve information that is unrelated to the LucasFonts site or services.
Statistics and tracking
This website uses Matomo (formerly Piwik), an open source software for statistical evaluation of visitor access.
Matomo uses cookies to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website is stored on our Matomo web server. The IP address is anonymised immediately after processing and before it is stored.
You can decide whether a unique web analysis cookie may be stored in your browser in order to enable the operator of the website to collect and analyse various statistical data:
We are hosting the Matomo application on a web server provided by Amazon Web Services (AWS). The server is located in Frankfurt/Main, Germany. The collected data is not passed on to any third party.
AWS is a subsidiary of Amazon.com, Inc. or one of its affiliates. Please refer to Amazon’s privacy information: aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq.
SSL encryption
The data transmission between the web server and your browser is encrypted via SSL.
Embedded YouTube videos
On some web pages we embed YouTube videos, that are usually integrated via so-called iframes. When visiting such a web page, it opens a connection to the servers of YouTube. This will tell YouTube which pages you are visiting. If you are logged into your YouTube account, YouTube can assign your surfing behavior to you personally. You can prevent this by logging out of your YouTube account beforehand. Please refer to YouTube’s privacy notes: policies.google.com/privacy
Get in contact via contact form
If you use our contact form, we process and store your submitted data. This includes:
Name
Company (optional)
E-mail
Message
This is necessary for processing the conversation. The data will not be passed on to third parties. The data will be deleted as soon as the conversation is over and there is no longer any purpose for storage.
Ordering a catalog
If you use our catalog order form, we process and store your submitted data. This includes:
First name
Last name
Street address
Zip code
City
State/region
Country
Occupation (optional)
E-mail
Company
This is necessary for processing your catalog order. The data will not be passed on to third parties. The data will be deleted as soon as the catalog ist sent to you via physical mail and there is no longer any purpose for storage.
Registering an account
When registering an account for the purpose of purchasing fonts, some personal information will be collected:
First name
Last name
Company name
VAT ID
E-mail
Street
City
Zip/postal code
Country
Preferred payment method
E-Mail notification on font updates
E-Mail notification on newsletters
We collect this data in order to be able to identify you as a registered user or customer in the future, and to facilitate your use of the website and its shop. In applicable cases, your information will be used to issue multi-user license documents, re-deliver orders in the case of transmission failure and maintain your customer history.
Newsletter subscription
If you subscribe to our newsletter with our newsletter registration form, we process and store your submitted data. This includes:
E-mail
Name
The data will be deleted as soon as there is no longer any purpose for storage. For sending newsletters, we use a third party newsletter tool from Campaign Monitor, located in 201 Elizabeth Street, Sydney, NSW 2000 Australia. By using the registration form, your data gets also submitted to Campaign Monitor, in order to provide the newsletter service. Please refer to Campaign Monitor’s privacy notes: campaignmonitor.com/policies/#privacy-policy
You can change your newsletter subscription at any time on the Campaign Monitor website.
Payment via PayPal
If you order fonts and you decide to pay by PayPal, you will be asked to enter your PayPal account details:
User name
Password
We do not process this information on our servers. It is directly transmitted to PayPal. By selecting this payment option, you agree to the transfer of personal data required for payment processing.
The European operating company of PayPal is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. & Cie. S.C.A., 22–24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg. The applicable data protection provisions of PayPal may be retrieved under paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full.
Payment via credit card
If you order fonts and you decide to pay by credit card, you will be asked to enter your credit card details:
Name on card
Card number
Security code
Expiration date
We do not process this information on our servers. It is directly transmitted to Braintree, our partner for payment processing. By selecting this payment option, you agree to the transfer of personal data required for payment processing.
Braintree is a division of PayPal, Inc. The European operating company of PayPal is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. & Cie. S.C.A., 22–24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg. The applicable data protection provisions of PayPal may be retrieved under paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full.
Confidentiality
LucasFonts may store and disclose personal information as allowed or required by applicable law, including making disclosures that are necessary or advisable to (a) protect the rights, safety or property of LucasFonts or others and (b) conform to legal or regulatory requirements. Without your express approval, however, LucasFonts will not share (give away, trade, sell or rent) your personal information with third parties, but may collect and/or provide aggregate statistics about its website and users to other parties.
As a LucasFonts customer, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password and for restricting access to your computer, and you agree to accept responsibility for all activities that occur under your account or password. LucasFonts only sells to adults, who can purchase with a credit card, by bank transfer or PayPal. If you are under 18, you may use this website only with involvement of a parent or guardian. LucasFonts reserves the right to refuse service, terminate accounts, remove or edit content, or cancel orders in its sole discretion.
Links
This website may contain links to other websites. Other sites may also reference or link to our site. LucasFonts is not responsible for the privacy practices of these sites. This Privacy Policy solely applies to information collected and maintained by LucasFonts. The full text, as required by German law, of the disclaimer concerning the contents of websites by third parties to which this website may link, can be found on the Impressum page.
Security
We take seriously the security of all personal and non-personal information associated with our visitors and participants by using secure communications for all such data. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, we can not guarantee that communications between you and LucasFonts, and LucasFonts and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties.
Changes
LucasFonts may, without notice, change, modify or restrict access to this website, or the content of the pages at any time.
As a LucasFonts customer, you are responsible for maintaining and updating, as applicable, your Customer account information with current, accurate and complete information. You are requested to check if your information is still up-to-date when requiring a service such as the mailing of a catalogue or the download of products.
Your rights to information, correction and cancellation
You have the right to access and correct your personal information and privacy preferences at any time. To edit your registration information, simply log into your account settings. The registration automatically appears, and permits you to view and edit your address details. You may also access and correct your personal information and privacy preferences by writing us an e-mail to sales@lucasfonts.com.
LucasFonts Privacy Policy v2.5, November 2019
© 2000–2020 LucasFonts GmbH
